Satou-san!
（永井圭(ながいけい)）
佐藤(さとう)さん！
Everyone’s fed up with playing your games!
（圭）
みんな…
あんたの遊びに付き合うのには…
もう うんざりしてるんですよ！
（コウマ）
つまり 回収した神経ガスを
地下に散布し―
In short, the plan is to release the recovered
nerve gas underground,
and render Satou powerless?
佐藤を
無力化するということですか？
In order to avoid alerting Satou,
we can’t evacuate the citizens.
（総理大臣）
佐藤に察知されるのを防ぐため―
住民を避難させることは出来ない
About four hours remain.
Before then, we have to capture Satou at any cost!
（戸崎優(とさきゆう)）
残りは約４時間だ
（戸崎）
その前に 何としてでも
佐藤を捕獲する
Go, ghost!
（圭）
行け 幽霊！
Fight to the death to stop him!
（圭）
死ぬ気で止めろ！
I know that!
（圭ＩＢＭ）
分かってるよ！
（圭）
あの人は革命家でも策士でもない
He’s not a revolutionary or a tactician.
He’s just a player.
（圭）
ただの遊び人です
And that’s exactly why we have room
to take advantage of him.
（圭）
だからこそ つけいる隙が
あるんです
What do you plan to do?
（高橋(たかはし)）
どうするつもりだ？
Bury him alive.
生き埋めにする
（田中功次(たなかこうじ)）
うわっ
（佐藤）
考えたな
You put some thought into it.
（佐藤）
でも―
But... just when you thought you'd won...
勝ったと思った瞬間―
The rug gets pulled out from under you!
人は足をすくわれるんだ
W- What’s going on?
な 何だ？
あっ…
（鈴村(すずむら)）崩落か？
（高橋）やりすぎたのかよ
Are they digging in?
We overdid it!
No, the floor-
（圭）
いや 床が！
Tosaki-san!
（下村泉(しもむらいずみ)）
戸崎さん！
（泉）あっ ああっ！
（高橋）うわぁ
（中野攻(なかのこう)）うわぁ…
（圭）うわっ ああ…
（佐藤）
君たち全員ブチ殺してやる
I’ll kill... every last one of you-
（泉）
くっ…
We couldn’t defeat him?
倒せなかったってこと？
ゲーム スタートだ
Game... start!
♪目を醒せ　このdistiny♪
Me o samase seou destiny, nogarerarenai no nara
Open your eyes Take on destiny If you can’t escape
♪逃れられないのなら♪
♪正しさも過ちも
全てを飲み込み闘う♪
Munashisa mo ayamachi mo, Subete o nomikomi tatakau
The futility and mistakes take them all in and fight
Zawameku kokoro no yami o tsukasadoru kyoui
Menace rules the darkness of the murmuring heart
♪騒(ざわ)めく　心の闇を
司(つかさど)る脅威♪
♪理性を　失くしかけてる
人間の真理♪
Risei o nakushikaketeru, ningen no shinri
Human psychology almost losing rationality
♪僕は知る　その無意味さを♪
Boku wa shiru  Sono muimisa o
I know how meaningless it is
♪偽りの平穏さえ　砕け散るなら♪
Itsuwari no heion sae kudakechiru darou
If only the tranquility of lies is smashed up
♪抗(あらが)う影　落とす♪
Aragau kage o toosu
Fight through the opposing shadow
♪It's the end of escape
立ち上がる♪
The end of escape, tachiagaru, sono michi shika nai kara
The end of escape, Make a stand, That’s the only way
♪その道しかないから♪
Tadoritsuke boku ga mezashita chiisana sono kibou ni
Struggle towards that tiny hope I aimed for
♪辿り着け　僕が目指した
小さなその希望に♪
♪差し伸べた　その手から♪
Sashinobeta sono te kara, koboreochita yowasa wa
The weakness spilling over from that outstretched hand
♪零れ落ちた弱さは♪
Orokashisa mo ayamachi mo subete o nomikomi kurutta
The foolishness and mistakes, I’ve gone mad taking them all in
♪正しさも過ちも
全てを飲み込み狂った♪
I make promises too,
Satou-san.
This is...
（圭）
ここは…
ううっ あぁっ はぁっ…
はぁっ
（攻）
永井！　永井！
Nagai! Nagai!!
あっ
（米軍現場司令官）
何が起こった！？　探索チーム！
What happened? Search team!
An explosion!
（スピーカー音声:米軍兵士）
爆発です！
（米軍兵士）
Ｆ‐２地点で爆発と共に
大規模な崩落が発生！
At point F2, there’s been an explosion
and a large-scale collapse.
It seems like below the underground tunnel,
there's an even older passage.
地下坑道の下に
さらに古い地下壕(ごう)があるようです！
（高橋）
ああ ああっ！
えいっ
奥山(おくやま)たちとも連絡がつかねぇ
I can’t reach Okuyama and the others.
Nagai!
（攻）
永井！
（攻）永…
（圭）中野 黙れ！
Naga-
Nakano, shut up!
（瓦礫を降りて来る音）
（攻）永井
（圭）佐藤さんは！？
Nagai!
Where’s Satou-san?
（攻）
いない！　泉さんたちも！
He’s not here.
Neither are Izumi-san and the others!
（圭）ちっ！
（攻）あっちは行き止まりだ
That way’s blocked off!
What’s going on?
（高橋）
どうなってんだよ！
くそっ！　してやられたんだ
No idea!
But it looks like we were done in.
くっ
逆に埋められたってことか？
That we were the ones buried?
...Which means, the problem is Satou-san.
（圭）
問題は佐藤さんだ
倒せていなければ
必ず仕留めにやってくる
If he’s not defeated,
he’ll come after us while we’re not paying attention.
（銃撃音）
（一同）はっ！
Is it Satou?
Probably!
（攻）佐藤か？
（圭）恐らく
Then, the ones he’s fighting are...
じゃあ 応戦しているのは 戸崎…
Tosa-
Izumi-san!
泉さん！
Let’s go!
行くぞ！
Kuro-chan. Please!
クロちゃん お願い！
（銃声）
（泉ＩＢＭ）
なっ…！
私は物を大事にするタイプでね
I'm the type who keeps my things in
good working order.
さっきのやつ
The one from earlier!
（倒れこむ音）
Tosaki-san!
戸崎さん うっ…
駄目だね
It’s no good.
（銃声）
（泉）なっ…
はっ…
What’s the damage to the unit?
（米軍副官）
部隊の被害は？
（スピーカー音声:米軍兵士）
ありません
No damage!
（米軍副官）
トラップですね
It’s a trap.
Will there be a problem with releasing the gas?
（米軍現場司令官）
ガスの散布に問題は出るか？
The conditions have changed slightly, but
they’re all within our expectations.
多少条件が変わりますが
想定の範囲内です！
よし　では設置が完了したら
直ちに撤収しろ！
Very good.
Then, when the installation has been
completed, withdraw immediately.
（米軍兵士）
了解
Roger.
We’ll also withdraw in five minutes.
（米軍現場司令官）
我々も５分後に撤収だ
（泉）
はぁっ…
I can’t believe...
（戸崎）
まさか 君のお荷物になるとはな
I’m burdening you like this.
Please don’t worry about it.
（泉）
気にしないでください
これが私の仕事です…
This is my job-
（銃声）
（戸崎）ぐっ…
（泉）ぐっ…
You’re first up.
まずは 君たちからだ
Nagai-kun. Can you hear me?
（泉）
永井君 聞こえる？　永井くん！
Nagai-kun!
はっ…
（佐藤）
私の邪魔をしたことを―
I'm going to make you regret getting
in my way so much...
you'll wish you were dead!
死ぬほど後悔させてやる
（銃声）
（佐藤）ぐはっ！
（鈴村(すずむら)）
行けぇ！
Go!!
はっ！
（鈴村）
早く！
Hurry!
（銃声）
（空撃ちの音）
（鈴村）
うわっ
（刺す音）
（鈴村）ううっ…
まずは １人
One down.
（つかまれる音）
（佐藤）な なに？
What?
（鈴村）
くっ…
君は人間だろ？
You’re supposed to be human!
I’m a ghost.
亡霊だよ
武蔵(むさし)重工で 死んだはずなんでな
At Musashi Heavy Industries...
I should have died.
（手榴弾の栓を抜く音）
（爆発音）
はぁっ…！
うっ
（足音）
To the right!
（圭）
右だ
（銃撃音）
（一同）うわっ…！
Three people confirmed!
They’re ajin!
（対亜隊員）
３体確認！
（対亜新隊長）
亜人だ　全員確保
Take them all in!
（銃声）
You kids go on ahead!
ガキども先行け！
（圭）あ…
（攻）あ…
（戸崎）
ああっ
（泉）
頑張って 戸崎さん
Hang in there, Tosaki-san.
（戸崎）
ぎ… 銀行だ
The bank.
は？
In that safe-deposit box is the proof
that you’re an ajin.
そこの貸し金庫に…
君が亜人だという証拠が入ってる
Tosaki-san.
（泉）戸崎さん 何の話を…
（戸崎）黙って聞け
What are you talking about?
Be quiet and listen.
The key for the safe-deposit box
金庫の鍵は―
is in her hospital room.
彼女の病室だ
If you understand, then go.
（戸崎）分かったら 行け
（泉）ええ？
With this leg,
there's no way for me to escape.
（戸崎）
この足じゃどのみち逃げ切れん
But, surely Nagai-kun and-
（泉）
でも きっと 永井君たちが
うっ
I release you from your contract.
（戸崎）
契約は破棄する
Hurry up and disappear.
（戸崎）
さっさと消えろ
目障りだ
Get out of my sight!
（戸崎）
ああっ…
So I’m...
私は―
...free?
自由ってことですか？
Yeah.
（戸崎）
ああ
Live as you like.
好きに生きろ
（泉）
じゃあ―
Then...
I’m free to protect you, Tosaki-san.
戸崎さんを守るのも
自由ってことですね？
What an idiotic-
I won’t take orders anymore.
（戸崎）何を馬鹿なことを…
（泉）もう指示は受けませんよ
I was released from my contract.
（泉）
契約は破棄されましたから
戸崎さん
Tosaki-san.
Thank you... for the new life.
新しい人生をありがとう
Stop!
You can’t beat him!
よせ！　君では勝てない！
ああ
So you’re number two.
２人目は君か
ん…
（泉）
まだ 駄目か
I still can't manage...
（銃撃音）
（泉）あっ…
はぁ…
（銃を投げる音）
Stop it!
（戸崎）
やめろーっ！
（銃声）
（戸崎）ぐはっ…
I’ll let you meet your new self!
（佐藤）
新しい自分と対面させてやろう
うおぉ
（つかまれる音）
（佐藤）おうっ！
ん？
It’s Nagai.
（圭ＩＢＭ）
永井です
うおっ…
うわっ…
Your game is over, Satou-san!
あんたのゲームは―
もう 終わりですよ 佐藤さん
あ…
Aren't you a bit late?
（佐藤）
遅かったじゃないか
Excuse me.
（田中ＩＢＭ）
すいませんねぇ
I went the wrong direction.
（田中）
逆方向に行っちまってたもんで
くっ…
（車が走る音）
（ドアを閉める音）
Commander. This way.
（米軍兵士）
大佐 こちらです
（米軍現場司令官）設置は？
（米軍兵士）完了しています
How’s the installation?
Complete.
よし 命令を待て
Excellent.
Wait for orders.
（倒れる音）
くそっ
Shit!
ん…
ああっ ぐわっ
（圭）
ううっ…
（佐藤ＩＢＭ）
さっきの―
This is payback for earlier!
お返しだ！
（圭）
ううっ ああっ
うっ…
You-!
てめぇ！
うがぁっ…
ああ… くそっ…
Damn-
（攻）
うわぁ…！
ん…
Kuro-chan!
クロちゃん！
（泉）
あ！
I’m always taking care of you.
（田中ＩＢＭ）
てめぇには
いつぞや世話んなったからな
This time I’ll make sure you thank me.
（田中ＩＢＭ）
きっちり礼をさせてもらうぜ
くっ…
Hey, Tanaka-kun!
I’ll leave this to you.
（佐藤）
じゃあ 田中君
そっちはよろしく
Got it!
了解っす
ううっ…
There’s one thing I want to ask you, Nagai-kun.
一つ聞きたいんだけどね 永井君
Why do you get in my way?
君は なぜ
私の邪魔をするんだい？
Isn’t it obvious?
決まってるでしょう
With you around,
あんたがいたら―
I’ll never be able to live a quiet life!
静かに暮らすなんて
一生不可能だからですよ
Ha!
フン 君は私と同じだなぁ
You’re the same as me.
I’d rather you not lump me together
with a lunatic like yourself.
あんたみたいな イカれた人間と
一緒にしないでほしいですね
Let’s do this, ghost!
やるぞ 幽霊！
えいっ
うーっ
（たたく音）
（圭）うっ
（佐藤）
ん…
（壁にたたきつける音）
（佐藤）やーっ！
（圭）うがっ…あっ…
You are the same.
（佐藤）
いやあ 同じだよ
You want to live quietly.
君は静かに暮らしたい
私は心ゆくまで遊びたい
I want to play to the very bottom of my heart.
But this world won’t allow that!
でも この世界は
それを許してはくれない
ぐっ…
One more time...
もっかいだ 幽霊！
ghost!
はっ
ああ あ…
That’s why we’re doing what we
should to each other!
だから
お互いにやるべきことをやってる
（蹴る音）
（圭）ぐっ…
（圭）
ぐっ…はっ…あっ…
あっ…
さすがの永井くんも ふん
Of course you would, Nagai-kun.
As foolish as always.
打ち止めか
Kuro-chan!
クロちゃん！
（倒れる音）
That’s the result of experience in
battle, I suppose.
実戦経験の差ってやつだな
くっそ…
Damn it.
フッ
（刺される音）
（泉）うっ
（泉の叫び声）
クッ ざまぁねぇな
You get what you deserve.
あ… い… ずみさんを…
Let Izumi-san...  go....
は… なせ…
I’ll make you pay for that time at the hospital!
（田中ＩＢＭ）
病院時の借りを返させてもらうぜ
（泉）
ああっ…
（田中ＩＢＭ）
ああ？
（攻ＩＢＭ）
あ… い… ずみさんを…
Let Izumi-san... go...
はな… せ
What is this?
（田中ＩＢＭ）
何だよ てめぇもかよ
You too?
邪魔すんじゃねぇ…
Don’t get in my way!
（刺さる音）
ああ…
（泉）
はぁっ はぁっ…
（舌打ち）
うっ ううっ…
（倒れる音）
Less than five minutes remain.
（米軍オペレーター）
５分切りました
Release the key lock.
（米軍現場司令官）
キーロック解除
（米軍オペレーター）
た 大佐！　佐藤です！
Commander! It’s Satou!
（米軍オペレーター）
佐藤を捉えました！
We’ve got Satou!
Commander.
（米軍副官）
大佐…
くっ…
命令は
最も確実な捕獲方法を採れだ
The orders were to...
use the most surefire method to capture Satou!
（圭）
あっ はぁっ…
Do you remember my promise
at the research lab, Nagai-kun?
（佐藤）
研究所でした約束を覚えてるかい
永井君？
君の頭を切断するという約束だ
I said I would cut off your head.
今から その約束を
果たさせてもらうよ
And now I’ll fulfill that promise.
（圭）
はぁっ！
断頭した君の頭を拾い上げ―
I’ll pick up your severed head,
新しい頭が作られるさまを―
and make you watch as a new head is created.
You will watch until you die.
絶命するまで観察させる
You will no longer be yourself.
君はもう 君でなくなる
（圭）
うっ くっ う…
Then...
（佐藤）
そして―
I promise I’ll show the new you
the best show you’ve ever seen.
新しい君には 最高のショウを
見せると約束しよう
First...
まずは… 慧理子(えりこ)ちゃんだ
Eriko-chan!
はっ！
Next, Kaito-kun and your parents.
次に海斗(かいと)君と 君のご両親
それからトザキ君
下村さん 中野君
And then... Tosaki-kun.
Shimomura-san, Nakano-kun....
（佐藤）
彼ら全員を君の目の前で殺す
All of them,
I’ll kill them in front of your eyes.
Just like at Musashi Heavy Industries.
（佐藤）
武蔵重工でやったみたいにね
あ…
That is...
それが―
私の邪魔をした君に対する罰だ
your punishment for getting in my way.
うっ…
違う…
No...
I...
僕は…
ううっ
僕も約束しますよ 佐藤さん
I make promises too, Satou-san.
あんたがどこに行こうが―
Wherever you go...
必ず捜し出して 殺します
I will find you and kill you!
ああ…
Ah.
Farewell...
お別れだ
Nagai-kun!
永井君！
永井！
Nagai!! Nagai-kun!
（泉）永井君！
（佐藤）やーっ！
（刺される音）
（佐藤）ん？
（圭ＩＢＭ）
やっぱ 人助けなんて
するもんじゃないなぁ
Yeah, nothing good comes from saving people.
We’ll act as your pawns!
（圭ＩＢＭたちの話し声）
I won’t do it.
はぁ…
Hurry up and die.
（圭ＩＢＭたちの話し声）
Shut up.
It’s your fault my quiet life is all messed up.
Satou-san.
（圭ＩＢＭ）
佐藤さん
I’m sorry to have caused you trouble.
（圭ＩＢＭ）
お手数おかけしてすみません
（佐藤）
ぐはっ…
がはっ…
He was sick...
（圭ＩＢＭ）
仕方ないよ 病気だったんだ
that’s just what happens.
ぐわっ…
（圭ＩＢＭ）
おしっこしたい
I need to take a piss.
（圭ＩＢＭ）
人の痛みなんて分かります？
I should be the one saying that
As your immortal soldiers!
（圭ＩＢＭ）
それはこっちのセリフだし
（攻）
ああ…
（圭ＩＢＭ）
ここまでやるんだ
The flood phenomenon.
フラッド現象
（佐藤）
うわぁっ
Send out the IBM-
（圭ＩＢＭ）
いつまで待っても
米軍は来ませんよ
You can wait as long as you want,
but the U.S. forces aren’t coming!
（圭ＩＢＭ）
一人で可哀想だから
構ってやってただけだし
I only bothered with him because
he seemed pitiful and alone.
はぁっ…
Hey, Nagai-kun.
やあ 永井君
（銃撃音）
（ヘリコプターの音）
Go, go, go!
（米軍空挺(くうてい)指揮官）
行け 行け 行け
（佐藤）
いやあ…
（刺さる音）
（佐藤）うおっ
（倒れる音）
Don’t move!
（米軍空挺兵）動くな！
（圭）え？
Hey, wait.
（圭）
いや 待て 僕は… あっ
I’m-
Don't take him!
（攻）
こいつは違うって！　あっ…
（戸崎）
待て！
Wait.
Those ajin are under the protection
of the Japanese government.
そいつらは
日本政府の保護下にある亜人だ
それに
女の方は私の部下で人間だ
And that woman is a human, working under me.
（田中のうめき声）
Satou and Tanaka.
（曽我部(そかべ)）
佐藤と田中
そちらとは それで合意が
取れているはずですよ
We've already reached an agreement.
Withdraw.
（米軍空挺兵）
撤収だ
アメリカ側が 直前で
ガスの散布を思いとどまってな
So the American side gave up the plan of
using the gas just before it was time.
（曽我部）
先輩に感謝するんだな
I’m grateful, Senpai.
In exchange for stopping Satou,
佐藤を止める代わりに
君らの存在は不問にする
all of you will be pardoned, and free to go.
そんな馬鹿げた取引を
押し通したんだからな
Thanks to your persistence with
your idiotic arrangements.
Tosaki-san.
戸崎さん…
Don’t forget to erase my
responsibility for my crimes.
（戸崎）
私の罪の免責も忘れるなよ
（曽我部）
フフッ
（泉）
はぁ…
（攻）
エッヘへヘ…
（ヘリコプターの音）
This afternoon, within the government, the cabinet made
a new decision regarding measures concerning ajin.
（モニター音声:キャスター）
本日午後 政府内で―
新たな亜人保護法案が
閣議決定されました
After much deliberation, the National Diet has approved
a new bill making civil rights a reality for ajin.
今後 国会での審議を経て
可決される見通しで―
これにより
亜人にも事実上の―
市民権が認められると
されています
With the enactment of this measure-
（キャスター）
この法案制定の背景には…
Nagai-san.
（看護師）
永井さん 採血の時間ですよ
It's time for a blood sample.
（永井慧理子(ながいえりこ)）
あ…
（看護師）
あら また お兄さん見えたの？
Ah.
Did you see your brother again?
It's nice that you get along.
いいわねぇ 仲良しで
Yes.
（慧理子）
はい
あ いや
別に 仲いいわけじゃないけど…
Ah, wait.
It’s not like we get along that well.
That’s why he wanted to go out with me!
（学生１）
そんで 私が言ってやったわけよ
（学生２）
へぇ やるー
Eh, that’s something!
（学生２）それ 超やばくない？
（学生１）でしょー？
Isn’t that pretty awful?
Isn’t it?
（学生の笑い声）
That’s really funny.
（学生１）
ホント マジうけた
はっ！
（携帯のバイブレーター音）
（圭）あっ
ん？
はい
Yes.
久しぶりですね
It’s been a while, hasn’t it.
What happened?
どうしたんですか？
え…
Eh?
（銃撃音）
（ヘリコプターの音）
（指揮官）
急げ！　急げ！　急げ！　急げ！
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry!
（刺さる音）
I can’t believe they really exist.
（隊員１）
まさか 本当にいるとはな
Yeah.
I didn’t believe it until now.
（隊員２）
ああ いまだに信じられねぇよ
They’re humans that don’t die.
（隊員３）
死なない人間だぜ
いったいどうなって
やがんだろうな　なあ？
I wonder how the hell they get that way.
Right?
（隊員４）
いやあ まるでゲームだねぇ
Yeah, it’s almost like a game.
（隊員４）
あんな体があったら
最高に楽しいだろうなぁ
It’d be so much fun to have a body like that.
ああ…
Ah, I had a dream for the first
time in a long time.
いやあ なんか
久しぶりに夢見ちゃったよ
I can’t believe you can sleep
in a situation like this.
よく のんきに寝れますね
Even though we don’t know
what will happen to us now.
これから 何されるか
分からないってのに
What are you saying?
（佐藤）
何を言ってるんだ 君は
Obviously we’ll start our second playthrough.
（佐藤）
これから２周目を始めるに
決まってるじゃないか
（田中）
はぁ？　そんなのどうやって…
How are we going to do that?
（佐藤）
ん？
“作戦は奇をもって
よしとすべし”さ
I love it when a plan comes together,
Tanaka-kun.
（佐藤）
田辺(たなべ)くん
ええ？
（ヘリコプターの音）
（爆発音）
えっ…
When did it happen?
いつの話ですか？
（戸崎）
米軍が捕獲したすぐ後だ
Right after the U.S. forces took him into custody.
やつら
その事実を隠蔽(いんぺい)していてな
They kept that fact quiet.
I'll tell you the details when you get here.
（戸崎）
詳細はこちらで話す
We’ll pick you up shortly.
（戸崎）
すぐに迎えをやる
はぁ…
（舌打ち）
♪もう飽きたから交換しよう♪
Mou akitakara koukan shiyou
Since I'm tired of it, let's exchange it
♪お前が持ってる普通のと♪
Omae ga motteru futsuu no to
With the normal one that you are holding
♪キラキラしてる神のカードと♪
Kira kira shiteru kami no kaado to
A shining paper card and
Zara zara shiteru kami no kaado
A rough paper card
♪ザラザラしてる紙のカード♪
♪今度家に来たら♪
Kondo uchi ni kitara
Next time you come to my house
♪全部見せてやるよ♪
Zenbu miseteyaru yo dakara
I'll show you everything, so...
♪だから♪
♪校庭の隅に二人 風が吹いて♪
Koutei no sumi ni futari, kaze ga fuite ima
At the edge of the schoolyard the wind blows...
♪今なら言えるかな♪
nara ieru ka na?
can I say it now?
♪誰にも言わない言葉♪
Dare nimo iwanai kotoba
Words never spoken to another person
♪「優しくするから
遊びに来てよ」♪
Yasashiku suru kara asobi ni kite yo
I'll be gentle so come and play often
♪「何でもあげるよ ねぇ」♪
Nandemo ageru yo, ne
I'll give you anything, hey
Korekara zutto tomodachi de ite yo
Let's be friends forever
♪「これからずっと
友達でいてよ」♪